ANDRES FELIPE ARAQUE MORA

Full Stack Developer



ABOUT ME

I am a full stack developer with over 4 years of experience contributing to the development of web and desktop applications in the IT sector. My interest has always revolved around the javascript stack in combination with cloud computing. I enjoy cooperative work, challenges, being in constant learning, and taking the initiative to achieve the objectives in the assigned projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

···· Oct 2020 - Present

Tech Leader Full Stack Developer

Work tools:

AWS, Node.is, React, Python, Angular, Git, Java, Figma, Jenkins, Docker, Terraform, SonarQube, Postman, CastleMock.

Banco de Occidente - Grupo aval

- I participated in 2 digital projects of websites for the approval of a personal loan online.
- I reduced the loading time of serverless processes such as the cold start of lambda services in AWS.
- I developed a library in order to have a design consistency on the websites based on the bank's Design System.
- I provided training and best practices to programmers and new joiners in my team.

···· Jan 2020 - Oct 2020

Freelance Full Stack Developer

Work tools:

Node.js, Angular, MongoDB, Hosting VPS, Git, Bash, Docker, Postman

CreativeMood

- I planned and set up infrastructure resources for VPS hosting.
- I fixed security vulnerabilities such as clickjacking and weak encryption between client and server through SSL.
- I collaborated in the construction of the RESTful
- I participated in concept meetings for design, product, and UX to align feature specifications.
- I developed user interfaces according to the design.

CONTACT













Other skills









sonarqube

















EDUCATION

- Mechatronic Engineer at Universidad Autonoma de Occidente
- ICAgile Certified Professional

LANGUAGES

- Native Spanish
- English B1

···· Nov 2019 - Mar 2020

Project Engineer

Work tools:

Python, C, C++

Universidad Autonoma de Occidente

- Developed a fruit classification system using an artificial vision camera with deep learning in Python.
- Designed and implemented a graphical user interface for remote control of industrial processes from a computer over the internet.
- Programmed microcontrollers, PLCs, and robots to automate industrial processes without human intervention.

···· Jan 2019 - Sept 2020

Freelance Full Stack Developer

Work tools:

Node.is, Angular, Hosting elástico, Git, Bash, Docker, MariaDB, Postman

Farfalla Sachets Aromatizantes

- Systematized sales points at the national level to have control of products through a website.
- Implemented federated authentication for the entry of different roles.
- Developed a landing page for clients, vendors, and administrators.
- Planned and configured infrastructure resources to set up hosting.
- Collaborated in the construction of the RESTful

···· 2018 - 2019

Freelance Full Stack Developer

Work tools:

Node.js, Ionic, Google Cloud, Andorid Studio, Swift, Cloud SQL, Zeplin, Git, Bash, Docker, Postman

Sociedad Salazar & Alvarez SAS

- I participated in concept meetings with design and product to create a mobile application for the motel sector in Cali.
- I improved the refresh rate of the app for the customer's current location, establishment, and tracking between them.
- I collaborated in the deployment of beta versions in the Play Store.
- I collaborated in the development of user interfaces depending on the features.
- I improved the loading time of the mobile application when entering it and its booking status.

WORK SETUP

My usual work canvas consists of Visual Studio Code, Jira, Chrome, Slack, Figma, Git, Postman, and Intellij IDEA, in an Agile methodologies environment under the SCRUM framework.



CONTACT









